Mustafa Yıldırım

Medior Software Engineer

PROFILE

As a back end software engineer with 4+ years of professional experience, I am passionate about learning and sharing solutions to complex problems. My expertise lies in improving software performance, refactoring micro-services, and developing infrastructure enhancements. I combined and refined my power by gathering information and know-how from different domains, people.

EXPERIENCE

Medior Software Engineer (Orion Innovations - Evalink) — 2022/12-Present Development and maintenance of an alarming management platform Evalink as full-stack. AWS ecosystem is used. Spring Boot on Kotlin with Java 17 , AngularJS are used. Alarming Domain fundamentals were achieved. Low-level network traffic practices are implemented by nature of alarming domain. Mentoring various levels of internees students is done

Medior Software Engineer(Orion Innovations - AT&T <u>CPaaS</u>) — 2020/01-2022/12 Involved development of 2 micro services(Spring Boot&Java) from scratch which are deployed on-premises k8s cluster. PoC works are demonstrated for different purposes(architecture design, performance tests, technology decision) . Involved design and development of an adapter microservice. Performance refactoring is done for billing microservice resulting decrease of query times from 2 minutes to 15-20 seconds on stored procedures. Local development environment is designed and developed by utilizing virtualization technologies to provide solid environment.

Junior Software Engineer (NETAŞ- <u>KandyLink</u>) — 2019/06-2020/01 Java 7 and EJBs are used development of a webRTC gateway (KandyLink). Scripting (Bash) is used to develop platform scripts which deploys on N-tier software architecture.

Intern Software Engineer(NETAŞ- <u>KandyLink</u>) — 2019/02-2019/06 Transformed an old pager tool(HTML,JS) to a modern <u>M[ysql]ERN stack</u>.

EDUCATION

Ozyegin University - Computer Science - 100% Performance Scholarship - 12/2019

SKILLS

Kotlin, Angular JS, aws, Java , Netty, Java 8 , Maven Spring Boot, JUnit, Mockito , Docker , multipass, vagrant, Kubernetes , Bash , Linux, Hazelcast , Rabbit MQ, Redis, Netflix Conductor, Spring Batch , Hibernate, Spring JPA, RESTful APIs, Swagger, MySql, MinIO , git, github, bitbucket, Sonar Qube, Jenkins, Intelij, Eclipse , VScode .